Finding Aid for Jens Jensen Drawings and Papers 1903-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Drawings
  - B
    - Babson, Henry B., Riverside, Illinois (Louis Sullivan, architect)
      - Design for entrance and grape arbors. Garden of H. Babson Esq., 1910; BAH3; Black and red ink on linen; with roof and floor plans and side and end elevations; signed.; 103 cm x 40 cm.; Scale: 1/4"" = 1' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Planting plan. Estate of H. Babson. Section #1, 1910; BAH4; Black and red ink on linen, indicates location and type of vegetation for portion of estate; signed.; 90 cm x 63 cm.; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Planting plan. Estate of H. Babson. Section #2, 1910; BAH5; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of vegetation for area surrounding residence; signed.; 70 cm x 66 cm.; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Planting plan. Estate of H. Babson. Section #3, 1910; BAH6; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of vegetation for portion of grounds; signed.; 81 cm x 61 cm.; Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Revised plan and planting plan of new section. Grounds of Mr. H. B. Babson., 1912; BAH7; Ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of vegetation proposed for entire estate; signed.; 59 cm x 74 cm.; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - A planting plan for the garden of Henry Babson, Esq. Revised, February 1916; BAH8; Ink on linen, indicates location and types of vegetation and location of walkways in garden area; signed.; 87 cm x 57 cm.; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Approximate boundary survey. Estate of Henry Babson, Esq., 1916; BAH9; Pencil on tracing paper; ""A.G.S."", del.; signed.; 59 x 62 cm.; Scale: 1"" = 50' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Plat of survey, 1916; BAH10; Blueprint; executed by Chicago Guaranty Survey Co.; unsigned.; 78 x 50 cm.; No Scale (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - Plat of survey, 1916; BAH11; Blue ink, pencil on heavy paper; plantings, pool sketched in pencil; notes; plat executed by Chicago Guaranty Survey Co.; unsigned. 88 x 110 cm. No scale. (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
      - A planting plan for the estate of H. Babson, Esq., 1917; BAH12; Red and black ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of vegetation proposed, location of buildings, roadways, present plantings and some topographical lines; signed, with initials of associates. 101 cm x 86 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 46, Folder 7)
    - Baker, E.E., Kewanee, Illinois
      - Planting plan for the estate of E. E. Baker Esq., 1917; BAK1; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings around residence; unsigned. 60 cm x 64 cm. Scale: 1"" = 16' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Approach drawing, 1917; BAK2; Blueprint; plan of grounds, contour lines, location of trees, walkways, etc; unsigned. 61 x 50 cm. Scale: 1"" = 16' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Planting plan. Estate of E. E. Baker, BAK3; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings and walkways around residence; signature smudged. 48 cm x 43 cm. Scale: 1"" = 16' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
    - Balhatchet, William, Evanston, Illinois
      - Planting design. Mr. William Balhatchet, 1910; BAL1; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings and location of arbors; signed. 67 cm x 23 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
    - Bangs, Geneva, Illinois
      - Bangs, 1927; BAM1; Pencil on tracing paper; appears to be plan of subdivision; unsigned. 88 x 57 cm. Scale: 1"" = 40' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
    - Mary L. Banks, Delafield, Wisconsin
      - Plan of grounds of Miss Mary L. Banks., 1914; BAN1; Fastened with tape to BAN1a; ink and watercolor (?) on tracing paper, untitled, undated, indicating roadways and buildings, ""removed"", ""added"", and ""remaining"" (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Plan of grounds of Miss Mary L. Banks., 1914; BAN1a; Fastened with tape to BAN1; ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; signed (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Miss Mary L. Banks [on verso: Survey and planting plan. Miss Banks], BAN2; Ink on linen, title and location in pencil, indicates elevations, topographical lines and distances; unsigned. 88 cm x 45 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
    - Barber, O.C., Akron, Ohio
      - A preliminary sketch for the estate of Mrs. O. C. Barber, 1922; BAR1; Blue, green, orange, black pencil on tracing paper, indicates positions of vegetation, gardens, roadways; few distances or types of plantings indicated; unsigned. 143 cm x 78 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - A planting plan for the area along the brook. Estate of Mrs. O. C. Barber and Mr. L. D. Brown, 1926; BAR2; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings; unsigned. 144 cm. x 55 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - An overlay of sketch for the property of Mrs. O. C. Barber, 1926; BAR3; Blue, green, red, black pencil on tracing paper, indicating buildings, roadways, vegetation with notes on uses of various portions of estate; yellow triangles indicate angles of photographs. 89 cm x 85 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Untitled [on verso: Mrs. Barber, Mrs. (sic) Brown, Akron, Ohio], 1922; BAR4; Blue, green, orange, black pencil on tracing paper, indicates brook, orchards and topographical lines with some elevations; unsigned. 180 cm x 89 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - No title, BAR5; Orange, green, blue, black pencil on tracing paper; roadways, vegetation, brook, pool, garden, residence, footpaths; on verso, ""? Brown and Barber""; unsigned. 140 x 84 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
    - Barker, Mrs., Michigan City, Indiana
      - No. I Sketch for garden. Mrs. Barker, 1909; BAT1; Pencil, green, blue, purple, red watercolor on tracing paper; location of circular pool, urns; location, type of plantings; notes; signed. 46 x 34 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Sketch for garden. Mrs. Barker, 1909; BAT2; Pencil, blue, green, purple, red watercolor on tracing paper; location of square pool, plantings; right edge cut away; signed. 37 x 46 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Sketch for formal garden., 1909; BAT3; Ink, blue pencil, blue, green, purple, orange watercolor on tracing paper; location of pool, urns, plantings, walks; signed. 85 x 46 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - In. IV. Sketch for remodeling formal garden of Mrs. Barker, 1909; BAT4; Pencil, blue, purple, green, red watercolor on tracing paper; some planting types; pool, urns, walks; signed. 46 x 37 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
        (neg. # BAT4)
    - Barnett, O.R., Glencoe, Illinois
      - Planting plan. Grounds of Mr. O. R. Barnett., 1912; BAV1; Ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; signed. 72 cm x 71 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
        (neg. # BAV1)
    - Barr
      - Private grounds, BAX1; Blueprint; drain and topo plans for farm; sheet numbered 11; name ""Barr"" given along south property line; unsigned. 71 x 49 cm. Scale: 1"" = 100' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Private grounds, BAX2; Blueprint; drain and topo plans for farm; sheet numbered 12; name ""Barr"" given along south property line; unsigned. 71 x 49 cm. Scale: 1"" = 100' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Private grounds, BAX3; Blueprint; drain and topo plans for farm; sheet numbered 13; name ""Barr"" given along south property line; unsigned. 71 x 49 cm. Scale: 1"" = 100' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
      - Private grounds, BAX4; Blueprint; drain and topo plans for farm; sheet numbered 14; name ""Barr"" given along south property line; unsigned. 71 x 49 cm. Scale: 1"" = 100' (Map-case 47, Folder 8)
    - Beiger, Mrs. Martin, Mishawauka, Indiana (Durham & Schneider, architects)
      - Grounds of Mrs. Martin Beiger...Tape survey., 1914; BEI1; Ink on linen, indicates location of residence, walkways, trees; signed. 89 cm x 52 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Grounds of Mrs. Martin Beiger...Sketch, 1914; BEI2; Blue, green, purple, yellow, orange, black pencil on tracing paper; sketch of grounds, with plantings, pool, gardens; many notes penciled in; signed. 85 x 49 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Grounds of Mrs. martin Beiger...Planting plan., 1914; BEI3; Ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; signed. 87 cm x 49 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
    - Bensinger, B.E., Glencoe, Illinois
      - Plan for waterpipes. Grounds of Mr. B. E. Bensinger, 1910; BEN1; Black and red ink on linen, indicates location of waterpipes; signed. 100 x 41 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Planting plan. Estate of B. E. Bensinger, 1910; BEN2; Black and red ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings; signed. 100 x 41 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
    - Benton Harbor, MI. Parks. Klock Park
      - Topographical survey of Klock Park, 1917; BEP 1; Photocopy; signed. 88 x 65 cm. Scale: 1"" = 100' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-1)
      - Survey of Klock Park, including proposed addition, 1918; BEP2; Red, black ink on linen; signed. 57 x 75 cm. Scale: 1"" = 200' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-2)
      - Sketch plan of bath house for Klock Park, 1918; BEP3; Pencil on tracing paper; elevations, plan; unsigned. 68 x 38 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-3)
      - Detail plan showing the grading and drainage. Kloch Park., 1919; BEP4; Black and red ink on linen. Area divided into 8 sections. 152 x 73 cm. Cale: 1"" = 100' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-4)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section I., 1920; BEP5; Yellow, black ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; signed. 104 x 85 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-5)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section II., 1920; BEP6; Yellow, black ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; signed. 104 x 78 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-6)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section III., 1920; BEP7; Yellow, black ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; signed. 101 x 71 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-7)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section IV, 1920; BEP8; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; signed. 75 x 65 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-8)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section V, 1920; BEP9; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; signed. 101 x 73 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-9)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park. Section 6, 1920; BEP10; Yellow, black ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; tennis courts; signed; 135 x 89 cm; Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-10)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section VII, 1920; BEP11; Yellow, black ink on linen; location, type of plantings; signed. 128 x 76 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-11)
      - Planting plan for Klock Park...Section VIII, 1920; BEP12; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; signed. 126 x 86 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # JEN-Bep-12)
    - Berryman, J.B., Downer's Grove, Illinois
      - Estate of J. B. Berryman...Plan of topo. survey, 1913; BER1; Black and red ink on linen, with elevations, topographical lines, locations of buildings, roads, trees; signed. 87 x 69 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Estate of J. B. Berryman...Grade plan for vegetable garden and terrace., 1913; BER2; Ink on linen, indicates elevations, with three cross-sections illustrating grade, walls, etc.; signed. 38 x 32 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Estate of J. B. Berryman. Grade plan for vegetable garden, 1913; BER3; Ink on linen, an enlargement of BER2; signed. 77 x 65 cm. Scale: 1"" (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Estate of J. B. Berryman...Planting plan...Section, 1913; BER4; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings; signed. 70 x 74 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
      - Estate of J. B. Berryman...Road plan., 1913; BER6; Ink and pencil on tracing paper; indicates grade, location of old road, with cross-section of proposed road and instructions for its composition (scale: 1"" = 1'); right side of sheet torn away; signed. 85 (approx.) x 39 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
        (neg. # BER7)
    - Bethany Bible School, Chicago, Illinois
      - Block plan showing grouping of buildings fr the Bethany Bible School, 1915; BET1; Blueprint, yellow, black pencil; unsigned. 52 x 53 cm. Scale: 1/16"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 9)
    - Bishop, D.H., Dowagiac, Michigan
      - Topographical survey. Estate of D. H. Bishop, Esq., 1909; BIS1; Red and black ink on linen, with elevations, topographical lines and locations of buildings, walkways and trees; signed. 70 x 73 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Sketch No I. Gardens for Mr. Bishop, 1909; BIS2; Pencil and watercolor on tracing paper, note initialed J.J., ""Details can be selected from either plan for a final plan.""; signed. 52 x 60 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Design for estate of D. H. Bishop, 1909; BIS3; Black and red ink on linen, indicates location of residence, pool, gardens, tennis court, walkway, arbors, etc., and location and type of plantings; signed. 70 x 53 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Garden plan for estate of D. H. Bishop, Esq., 1909; BIS4; Black and red ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings for flower garden area; signed. 74 x 52 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Plan for walks, drainage and grading for estate of D. H. Bishop, 1909; BIS5; Red and black ink and pencil on linen, indicates elevations, drains, with several cross-sections illustrating grade; signed. 77 x 67 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Design for concrete garden walls. D. H. Bishop, Esq., 1910; BIS6; Red, black ink on tracing paper; sections, elevations; signed. 82 x 47 cm. Scale: 1/8"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Design for lamp posts. Mr. D.H. Bishop, 1910; BIS7; Red and black ink on linen, details design and components for lamp posts, including glass windows; signed; 88 x 35 cm; Scale: 1 1/2"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Concrete bench for Mr. D. H. Bishop, 1910; BIS8; Red and black ink on linen, details design and components for lamp posts, including glass windows; signed. 88 x 35 cm. Scale: 1 1/2"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Design for garden house and pergola. Estate of D.H. Bishop, 1910; BIS9; Red and black ink on linen, details plans for floor, roof, ceiling, with cross-sections, elevations, floor plans and views of structure; 102 x 51 cm; Scale: 1/4"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Untitled [name on verso], BIS10; Red ink and pencil on tracing paper, indicates elevations, topographical lines, location of buildings, walkways, gardens, etc., with cross-section of pool and occasional notes; unsigned. 71 x 70 cm. No scale. (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
    - Blum, H.H., Chicago, Illinois
      - A planting plan for the burial lot of Mr. H. H. Blum. Rose Hill Cemetery, 1921; BLU1; Ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; walkway and corrections in planting location penciled in; signed. 33 x 26 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - A planting plan for the burial lot of Mr. H. H. Blum. Rose Hill Cemetery, 1921; BLU2; Ink on linen, incorporates changes noted on BLU1; signed. 33 x 26 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
    - Blumenthal, Oscar, Glencoe, Illinois
      - A planting plan of the home grounds of Mr. Oscar Blumenthal, 1926; BLW1; Black and yellow ink on linen (some pencil), indicates location, type and amount of plantings, location of walkways, vegetable garden, camp fire, walls, etc.; unsigned. 41 x 71 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
    - Boles, F.T., Hinsdale, Illinois.
      - Planting plan, 1909; BOL1; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings; unsigned. 80 x 45 cm. Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Mr. F. T. Boles., 1909; BOL2; Blueline print, pencil; Swain, Nelson and Sons, Co., landscape architects; plan of grounds; unsigned. 49 x 32 cm. (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Design for crematory. Mr. F. L. (sic) Boles, 1909; BOL3; Pencil, red and black ink on tracing paper; plan, elevation; signed. 41 x 25 cm. Scale: 1"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Designs for pergolas and clothes poles for garden of Mr. F. L. Boles, 1909; BOL4; Red, black ink on tracing paper; elevations; unsigned. 80 x 25 cm. Scale: 1/2"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
    - Booth, Sherman, Glencoe, Illinois (Frank Lloyd Wright, architect).
      - Property of Mr. Sherman Booth, 1911; BOO1; Pencil on linen; survey of grounds; signed. 23 x 18 cm. Scale: 1"" = 200' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Plat of topographical survey. Grounds of Mr. S. M. Booth, 1911; BOO2; Pencil, ink on linen; elevations; buildings, pool, vegetation; signed. 99 x 79 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Planting plan. Grounds of Mr. Sherman M. Booth, 1912; BOO3; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; gardens, pool, tennis court; elevations; residence by Frank Lloyd Wright; signed. 95 x 80 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
      - Water and drain plan. Grounds, 1912; BOO4; Ink on linen; elevations, tile lines; gardens, pool, buildings; signed. 93 x 80 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 10)
    - Born, M., Glencoe, Illinois
      - Plan of topographical survey for the estate of Mr. M. Born Esq, 1915; BOR1; Ink on linen; two sheets; with elevations, location of roads and larger trees; signed. 87 x 115 cm (both sheets) Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Plat of topographical survey for the property of M. Born Esquire, 1915; BOR2; Red and black ink and pencil on linen, indicates elevations, topographical lines, vegetation, buildings, etc. 124 x 90 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Detail cross-section of water--sewer--telephone and electric light service for the estate of M. Born, Esq, 1916; BOR3; Black and red ink on linen; unsigned. 32 x 22 cm. Scale: 1"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Estate of M. Born Esq...Plan of the south east portion of property showing location of storm sewer and manholes within 33' bounds north of south property line., 1916; BOR4; Black and red ink on linen; signed. 69 x 38 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - The property of M. Born Esquire, 1916; BOR5; Red and black ink and pencil on linen, indicates storm sewer and water lines, with elevations between five clusters of residences on property; signed. (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Estate of M. Born, Esq. Preliminary sketch of the clearing and the north side of the property....Section I, 1916; BOR6; Pencil and red pencil on tracing paper, indicates location and type of plantings; unsigned. 155 x 58 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Estate of M Born, Esq. Planting plan for that portion of the property lying south of the center of the clearing...Section II, 1916; BOR7; Pencil and red pencil on tracing paper, indicates location and type of plantings; unsigned. 130 x 62 cm. Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Development of the grounds. Estate of M. Born, Esq., 1916; BOR8; Ink on linen, indicates location of residences, with floor plans, of plantings, walkways, gardens, pools, etc.; signed. 125 x 88 cm. Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Estate of M. Born, Esq. Planting plan for that portion of the property lying south of the center of the clearing. Section II, 1917; BOR9; Pencil on tracing paper, indicates location, type, and amount of plantings; signed; spilled ink defaces portion of lower right; 130 x 63 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Estate of M. Born, Esq. Preliminary sketch of north side of property, 1917; BOR10; Pencil on tracing paper, indicates location, type, and amount of plantings; unsigned; 134 x 58 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Vegetable garden. Estate of M. Born, Esq., 1917; BOR11; Pencil on tracing paper; unsigned; 35 x 39 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Detail plan of E. Born pool. Estate of M. Born, Esq., 1917; BOR12; Pencil on tracing paper; unsigned; 47 x 29 cm; Scale: 1"" = 2' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Detail plan of pool. Estate of M. Born., 1917; BOR13; Pencil on tracing paper; unsigned; 82 x 25 cm; Scale: 1"" = 2' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - A planting plan for the garden areas. Estate of M. Born., 1917; BOR14; Pencil on tracing paper, indicates location, type, and amount of plantings; note under title, ""del. F.E.H.""; unsigned; 112 x 80 cm (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - A planting plan for the garden areas. Estate of M. Born, BOR15; Pencil on tracing paper; right edge torn away; appears to be working sketch from which BOR14 was made; numerous blue check marks and handwritten planting types; unsigned; 90(approx.) x 77 cm; Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Pool for estate of M. Born, Esq., 1917; BOR16; Pencil on tracing paper, with cross-section detail and overview; note in another hand, ""Foreman's Pool""; signed; 48 x 27 cm; Scale: 1"" = 2' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - The garden area. Residence of H.E. Foreman. Estate of M. Born, 1917; BOR17; Pencil on tracing paper, indicates location, type, and amount of plantings; cross-section of pool and adjoining area at bottom; unsigned; note ""del. F.E.H.""; 63 x 62 cm (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Plan of the Rosenbaum Pool. Estate of M. Born, 1917; BOR18; Pencil on tracing paper, with detailed cross-sections; unsigned; 50 x 23 cm; Scale: 1"" = 2' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - The garden areas about the residence of E.S. Rosenbaum. Estate of M. Born, 1917; BOR19; Pencil on tracing paper; location, type of plantings; pool, footpaths; unsigned; 51 x 62 cm; Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - The garden area about the residence of E.S. Rosenbaum. Estate of M. Born, 1917; BOR20; Pencil on tracing paper, indicates location, type, and amount of plantings; unsigned; 51 x 62 cm; Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - Plan showing framing of playhouse. Estate of M. Born, Esq., 1917; BOR21; Pencil on tracing paper; plan, elevations; notes; unsigned; 38 x 26 cm; Scale: 1/2"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
      - House in vegetable garden for M. Born, Esq., 1917; BOR22; Pencil on tracing paper; plan, elevation; notes; signed; 31 x 52 cm; Scale: 1/2"" = 1' (Map-case 47, Folder 11)
    - Boynton, Mrs., Ravinia, Illinois
      - Plan of formal garden for Mrs. Boynton, 1918; BOY1; Pencil on tracing paper; very simple sketch; unsigned; 50 x 54 cm; Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 47, Folder 12)
    - Brooks, Harold C., Marshall, Michigan
      - A topographic plan of the property of Mr. Harold C. Brooks, 1921; BRK1; Blue, yellow, black ink on linen; topo. lines, elevations; pencil revisions; unsigned; 155 x 44 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 12)
      - A grading plan for the property of Mr. H.C. Brooks., 1921; BRK2; Blue, brown, black ink on linen; contour lines for present, proposed grades; signed; 120 x 44 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 47, Folder 12)
      - Plan for spring and rock ledges. The estate of Mr. H.C. Brooks, 1922; BRK3; Yellow, black ink on linen; plan, cross-sections; details; notes; signed (Map-case 47, Folder 12)